The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Twenty-Ninth Episode
The Melted Icicle
Sapphire, blinded,
has been taken away by Mephisto.
She knows that the King and the Queen
are on the Island of Snakes..
..turned into stone statues.
Helped by Hecate, daughter of Mephisto,
she tries to help them, but falls into the sea
She is saved by the pirate Blood
With him she goes to the magic spring..
...and thanks to the miraculous water
she regains her sight.
Then she returns to Coolland to
fight Queen Icicle,
who has built a new
powerful weapon: the iron lion.
Sapphire confronts him
and manages to destroy him.
But in the battle, her
friend Tink is hit...
..and Sapphire
believes him dead.
Hecate arrives to warn Sapphire
that her father and mother...
...are in danger, because Mephisto
wants to smash their statues to pieces.
Sapphire sets off immediately
for the Island of Serpents.
What are you waiting for? Make
a second iron lion immediately!
Send a mission to
the Crystal Valley!
It's horrible! The Queen
is a terrible woman...
...for having asked to
make such a weapon!
Arrest that young man!
He spoke ill of the Queen!
I'm saved! Incredible!
I'm afraid that Sapphire
is worried about me.
Hey, Sapphire, where
are you? Sapphire!
I will ask the birds,
they will know!
Can you tell me where Sapphire is?
Welcome, Sapphire!
Listen, Mephisto, I have come here.
...because I want you to
help my father and my mother.
All right! I will do it if you promise
me that you won't run away.
I won't run away! I
swear on my sword...
...that I won't run away!
- All right, then!
Alé Satàn!
- Oh, my dear!
- Your Majesty!
- How do you feel?
- Fine, I think!
Father! Mother!
- I think I heard Sapphire's voice.
- Me too!
Alé Satàn!
Poor thing! Can't you send
Sapphire's parents to the castle?
Forget about them! I can't
always take care of them!
How mean you are!
They will starve to death!
Shut up!
There are people on
the Island of Serpents!
- People?
- Yes, Your Majesty!
And the people on the island are
the King and Queen of Silverland!
Show me! Go there
immediately, we must catch them!
Yes, Queen!
- Stop! You are under arrest!
- What are you doing? We are not criminals!
My daughter..
...tonight you will be born
a second time!
I couldn't wait
for this moment to arrive
You will be a witch
with a heart of stone!
In celebration of the birth
of my witch...
Thunder, lightning, toast!
Are you tired? Now I'll have someone
take over for you, we're almost there!
My hands are paralyzed!
Cursed Mephisto, go away!
Wait for me, dad!
Sapphire!
- Tink! So you're alive!
- Of course I'm alive! Look!
Look!
That is the Island of Snakes!
But... there is no one there!
As I predicted, Mephisto has sent
my father and my mother away.
It's incredible,
such a kind devil!
Anyway, I'm going back to Silverland.
Hey, who's there?
No, it's just a passing bird!
- We'll wait for you next year!
- Thank you, birds!
Tink, come on, hurry!
- Is this the entrance to the secret passage?
- Shut up!
Why do you want to enter
through the secret passage?
Because, as I told you, there
is a fake Sapphire in the castle!
Let's go this way because
otherwise they might.
...send us back
like last time.
If we go left
we'll reach the crypt!
Look, this is moving!
Up!
Be careful not to fall
into that old well!
What a terrible place
this is! My goodness!
Don't move,
someone is coming!
It's you! How did you get here?
This damn fake Sapphire!
I will kill you!
I think she's dead!
- But this is my room!
- Now we are safe!
Don't be afraid.
It's an eagle, don't you see?
An eagle?! How beautiful and big it is!
Who knows where it comes from? Hello! Hello!
This is a letter!
- What does it say?
- My father and my mother.
...have been taken
by Queen Icicle!
How the hell did that happen?
Luckily we managed
to take prisoner...
- the King and Queen of Silverland!
- Then it's true!
All this thanks
to the great power of the Queen.
Tomorrow the Queen herself
will send a letter to Silverland..
...asking them to surrender.
You will pretend to be Sapphire until
the very end, you will come to Coolland...
...and you will affix
the seal of surrender!
No!
- I can't!
- But if you don't surrender
Your father and your mother will face
real danger.
Then what can I do?
How can I help
my father and my mother...
...and at the same time
protect Silverland?
I don't know either.
Anyway, what is certain,
...is that we must destroy
Queen Icicle.
- Queen Icicle?!
- Yes!
But even if you are strong,
you cannot do such a thing...
...because there are many soldiers
following the Queen.
Tink! Yes, I can do it!
It's easy for me!
I will pretend to be the fake Sapphire
and I will go visit the Queen.
If Sapphire were to die
it would be truly terrible!
I must help her at all costs
The eagle is gone!
I've got it!
I'll ask Peter of the woods!
Peter!
Hey, Peter!
Hi, Peter! Hi!
I have to ask you a favor, please!
Take me to the Crystal Valley!
The Crystal Valley...
There are many people there
who love Sapphire.
When I was there too,
they all treated me lovingly.
There are no bad people.
They were only brought there
because they opposed the Queen.
I want to free them somehow,
so they will help Sapphire!
Please, use your instinct to find
the hole the mice know, come on!
Thank you, Peter!
Goodbye!
Good morning!
Listen, I have to ask you a favor.
Please, call the largest
number of your friends possible!
Go down, now! From today
on, you will work in this valley!
How wicked he is!
You will pay for this!
I wonder
what Sapphire is doing now!
Princess Sapphire,
do your best!
Damn Nylon, he thinks
I'm the fake Sapphire.
Listen, now you can take off
your mask!
Your performance
was admirable!
Now you can speak freely
because it's just the two of us.
I don't even know his
name How can I deceive him?
Why aren't you speaking?
- Please, shut up!
- What?!
If I speak to you in a different
way than usual, Gelo will scold me!
So it's better if I don't
speak to you at all!
Yes, I know! Gelo is
very strict, you're right!
She's back!
Soon I will arrive
at Coolland Castle.
I might die...
Oh, no...
I won't be able to help my father and
my mother, if I let myself be overcome...
...by weakness.
I must be stronger!
What are you waiting for?
Soon we will reach the tunnel!
In the tunnel there is no
snow all the way to the castle!
Come on, damn it!
Don't be lazy!
Hurry up! And work!
Come on, charge!
But those are mice!
Thousands of mice!
Help!
Mice! Come on, little mice, fight!
Bite those arrogant soldiers!
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
We are free! We are free!
Friends, please, help Sapphire!
Let's defeat
Queen Icicle together!
She thinks I am the fake Sapphire.
Thank you for taking on
these troubles.
It was a real pleasure, Queen.
Now you can relax!
There is no one here,
except those who know
that you are the fake Sapphire!
- Yes...
- Now, if you affix the seal here
- Silverland will become mine!
- But before that, Your Majesty.
- What is it? - Have you really
captured the King and the Queen?
Because Duke Duralumin
is truly worried...
...and ordered me
to make sure of it.
How cowardly!
All right, I'll show them to you! Let's go!
Follow me.
- Sapphire!
- You are Sapphire, aren't you?
How stupid they are!
This is not your daughter!
- No?!
- I'm sure it's Sapphire!
Father! Mother!
Please, be quiet!
- Take off your mask!
- Of course, I'll take it off right away!
Open the cell if you don't
want me to kill the Queen!
Just as I thought!
You are...
- It's true, I am the real Sapphire!
- What are you saying?
I'll show you my other face!
You are the Phantom Knight!
We will take Ghiacciolo
as a hostage...
...and no one will hurt us!
- Thank you, Sapphire!
Let us pass!
Oh! Gelo!
Kill the Phantom Knight!
- Oh, mother..!
- Sapphire...
No!
It's an earthquake!
But it's lasting too long!
The water in the moat!
The water level is dropping!
Cursed prisoners!
Fire! Fire!
- It's time to defeat the
Queen - Come on, take up arms!
- Let's help our comrades!
- Come on, here! Take them! Take them!
Look,
the castle is burning!
Good!
Kill Queen Icicle!
The people managed to get inside!
- Let's kill her!
- Let's catch her and kill her!
What are
all my soldiers doing?
My Queen,
the soldiers have betrayed you!
They have joined the people
and are about to attack you!
Run away or you will die like me!
Quick, Gelo, let's escape!
Sapphire!
The Queen has escaped!
The fountain is a secret passage!
Here, this must be it!
Sapphire, please be careful!
Gelo!
Queen Icicle!
Oh, my God! Gelo!
Help! Help!
Help!
- The Queen has disappeared!
- Hooray!
Hooray!
No, people of Coolland!
It was you who helped me!
And so: long live Coolland!
- Long live!
- Hooray! Hooray!
- What is she saying?
- Nothing. She's just spoiled!
- Grand Duke, the King is coming!
- What?!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP